<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Celebrating | Antonina</title>
    <link>http://antonina1506.github.io/category/celebrating/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://antonina1506.github.io/category/celebrating/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Celebrating</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://antonina1506.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Celebrating</title>
      <link>http://antonina1506.github.io/category/celebrating/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 9th of May</title>
      <link>http://antonina1506.github.io/post/post_week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://antonina1506.github.io/post/post_week2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;victory-day&#34;&gt;Victory day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victory Day is a holiday that commemorates the victory over Nazi Germany in 1945. It was first inaugurated in the 15 republics of the Soviet Union, following the signing of the German Instrument of Surrender late in the evening on 8 May 1945 (after midnight, thus on 9 May Moscow Time). The Soviet government announced the victory early on 9 May after the signing ceremony in Berlin. Although the official inauguration occurred in 1945, the holiday became a non-labor day only in 1965, and only in certain Soviet republics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;celebration&#34;&gt;Celebration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1995, as the world celebrated the 50th anniversary of the end of the war, many world leaders converged on Moscow to attend the city&amp;rsquo;s first state sponsored ceremonies since the fall of the USSR. In 2015 around 30 leaders, including those of China and India, attended the 2015 celebration, while Western leaders boycotted the ceremonies because of the Russian military intervention in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;holiday-traditions&#34;&gt;Holiday traditions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victory Day Parades
Victory Day Parades are military parades that are held on 9 May, particularly in various post-soviet nations such as Russia, Kazakhstan, Belarus, and until 2015, Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mass processions
The Immortal Regiment (Russian: Бессмертный полк; Bessmertniy Polk) is a massive civil event staged in major cities in Russia and around the world every 9 May. Since it was introduced in 2012, it has been conducted in cities such as Moscow, Washington D.C., Dushanbe, Berlin, and Yekaterinburg. Participants carry pictures of relatives and/or family members who served during the Second World War. The front line of the procession carries a banner with the words Bessmertniy Polk written on it. Up to 12 million Russians have participated in the march nationwide in recent years. Since 2015, the President Vladimir Putin and senior Russian officials have participated in the procession in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;soviet-and-post-soviet-symbols-associated-with-the-victory-day&#34;&gt;Soviet and post-Soviet symbols associated with the Victory Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banner of Victory
The Victory Banner refers to the Soviet military banner raised by the Soviet soldiers on the Reichstag building in Berlin on 1 May 1945. Made during the Battle of Berlin by soldiers who created it while under battlefield conditions, it has historically been the official symbol of the Victory of the Soviet people against Nazi Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saint George&amp;rsquo;s Ribbon
The Ribbon of Saint George is a military symbol that dates back to the era of the Russian Empire. It consists of a black and orange bicolour pattern, with three black and two orange stripes. In the early 21st century, it became an awareness ribbon to commemorate the veterans of the war, being recognized as a patriotic symbol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-template-is-mobile-first-with-a-responsive-design-to-ensure-that-your-site-looks-stunning-on-every-device&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
