<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IT | Academic</title>
    <link>http://antonina1506.github.io/tag/it/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://antonina1506.github.io/tag/it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>IT</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://antonina1506.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>IT</title>
      <link>http://antonina1506.github.io/tag/it/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git. Software for tracking changes in any set of files.</title>
      <link>http://antonina1506.github.io/post/post_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://antonina1506.github.io/post/post_git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git&amp;rsquo;s design was inspired by BitKeeper and Monotone. Git was originally designed as a low-level version-control system engine, on top of which others could write front ends, such as Cogito or StGIT. The core Git project has since become a complete version-control system that is usable directly. While strongly influenced by BitKeeper, Torvalds deliberately avoided conventional approaches, leading to a unique design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git&amp;rsquo;s design is a synthesis of Torvalds&amp;rsquo;s experience with Linux in maintaining a large distributed development project, along with his intimate knowledge of file-system performance gained from the same project and the urgent need to produce a working system in short order. These influences led to the following implementation choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong support for non-linear development
Git supports rapid branching and merging, and includes specific tools for visualizing and navigating a non-linear development history. In Git, a core assumption is that a change will be merged more often than it is written, as it is passed around to various reviewers. In Git, branches are very lightweight: a branch is only a reference to one commit. With its parental commits, the full branch structure can be constructed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed development
Like Darcs, BitKeeper, Mercurial, Bazaar, and Monotone, Git gives each developer a local copy of the full development history, and changes are copied from one such repository to another. These changes are imported as added development branches and can be merged in the same way as a locally developed branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compatibility with existent systems and protocols
Repositories can be published via Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP), File Transfer Protocol (FTP), or a Git protocol over either a plain socket or Secure Shell (ssh). Git also has a CVS server emulation, which enables the use of existent CVS clients and IDE plugins to access Git repositories. Subversion repositories can be used directly with git-svn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-structures&#34;&gt;Data structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways you can just see git as a filesystem—it&amp;rsquo;s content-addressable, and it has a notion of versioning, but I really designed it coming at the problem from the viewpoint of a filesystem person (hey, kernels is what I do), and I actually have absolutely zero interest in creating a traditional SCM system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git stores each revision of a file as a unique blob. The relationships between the blobs can be found through examining the tree and commit objects. Newly added objects are stored in their entirety using zlib compression. This can consume a large amount of disk space quickly, so objects can be combined into packs, which use delta compression to save space, storing blobs as their changes relative to other blobs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
